<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 08:59:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Part 2: 7 customer fears and how to address them</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 08:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20010</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Shoppers are more discerning and demanding than ever thanks to their increased experience with online merchants&#8211;they’re also better at telling a fake from the real deal. In part 2 of our article on responding to customer fears, we address some of the more practical details that make shoppers hesitate to click through to checkout. 1. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/">Part 2: 7 customer fears and how to address them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shoppers are more discerning and demanding than ever  thanks to their increased experience with online merchants&#8211;they’re also better at telling a fake from the real deal.<br />
In part 2 of our article on responding to customer fears, we address some of the more practical details that make shoppers hesitate to click through to checkout.<br />
<span id="more-20010"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#252934">1. I can’t tell if I’ll like the product.</h2>
<p>The biggest drawback to online shopping is that you can’t pick up and touch products, turn them around in your hands or squint at the tiny details. However, you can do a lot to give your customers an accurate idea of what your products look like, and how they should be worn or used: use detailed, benefits-oriented product descriptions to answer any questions your customers might have, complemented by a variety of professional product photos taken from many different angles and zoom levels. Customer reviews can help buyers get a sense of the product as well. Also, think about including a way to show the size and scale of your products.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/eatingtools-1024x685.jpg" alt="eatingtools" width="700" height="468" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20012" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="https://www.eatingtools.com/" target="_blank">Eatingtools</a> does a beautiful job of illustrating products and describing how they might be used and in what situations.</span></p>
<h2 style="color:#252934">2. It might not get here on time—or ever.</h2>
<p>Partner up with trusted shipping suppliers who have a reputation for on-time delivery and clearly list them on your site. Give your customers the option to track packages, which is especially appreciated for time-sensitive orders. If you do fail to meet a shipping date or a package goes missing, use it as an opportunity to show your outstanding customer service by offering a replacement, a free gift or a significant discount on a future purchase. Make your shipping guarantees clear and easy to find.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/sweet_isabelle-1024x346.jpg" alt="sweet_isabelle" width="700" height="236" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20059" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="http://www.sweetisabelle.com/" target="_blank">Sweet Isabelle</a> lets customers know they’ll receive a tracking number as soon as their order is processed and shipped.</span></p>
<h2 style="color:#252934">3. If I don’t like, I’ll be stuck with it.</h2>
<p>A clear exchange and returns policy is the best remedy to problem this. If you can offer free shipping and returns, even better. But make sure your business can handle the added cost. Whatever policy you decide on, make sure it’s easy to understand and free from confusing jargon. Make it easy to find on your website. </p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/smallable-1024x715.jpg" alt="smallable" width="700" height="488" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20058" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="http://en.smallable.com/" target="_blank">Smallable’s</a> return policy is clear and complete.</span> </p>
<h2 style="color:#252934">4. There won’t be help if I need it. </h2>
<p>Customer service is a crucial component of an ecommerce business, maybe even more so in some way than at in a brick and mortar store. Because you have no face-to-face interaction with your customers, you have to be on top of problems from a distance. Depending on your budget and resources, you have a few different options for providing customer service. </p>
<p>Start with a simple <strong>FAQ</strong> that addresses the major (and yes, minor!) questions your customers may have about your products, your return policy, where and/or how your products are made, etc.<br />
If you have the resources, set up a customer service phone number. <strong>Online chat</strong> is another way to let your customers know you’re there for them. </p>
<p>Just be sure that you can follow through on your promise of customer service. </p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/maspatule-1024x570.png" alt="maspatule" width="700" height="389" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20014" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="http://www.maspatule.com/" target="_blank">MaSpatule.com</a> clearly indicates their customer service number and guarantees. Highlighting trusted shipping carriers and policies doesn’t hurt either.</span></p>
<p><img src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/mamy_factory-1024x542.jpg" alt="mamy_factory" width="700" height="370" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-20013" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style:italic"><a href="http://www.mamyfactory.com/en/" target="_blank">Mamy Factory</a>’s FAQ addresses questions about everything from working policies to materials used.</span></p>
<p>What other customer fears have you encountered? Let us know in the comments. Ready to start your ecommerce store? Visit <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/">PrestaShop</a> today! </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/">Part 2: 7 customer fears and how to address them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-2-7-customer-fears-address/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Simple Content Ideas for your About Us Page</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 08:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20037</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’re like most writers, you find that writing about yourself always seems impossible. No matter how long you stare at the blank page, simply thinking about writing content about yourself brings on a bout of writer’s block. It’s probably the reason the content for your About page has gone unfinished… until now. Today we’re [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/">6 Simple Content Ideas for your About Us Page</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’re like most writers, you find that writing about yourself always seems impossible. No matter how long you stare at the blank page, simply <span style="font-style:italic">thinking</span> about writing content about yourself brings on a bout of writer’s block. It’s probably the reason the content for your About page has gone unfinished… until now.</p>
<p>Today we’re sharing 6 simple content ideas to help you write your About Us page. If you’re lacking content, we’ll give you examples of what you can include. If you have too much content,  we’ve also got you covered with helpful questions to narrow it down. Whether you’re drafting your About Us page for the first time or simply updating it, read on for content ideas. You’ll be done in no time!<br />
<span id="more-20037"></span><br />
Before you even start coming up with content, you’ll need to <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">identify your audience</a>. If you’re running an online store, the About Us page should be directed towards customers who want to get to know your brand better. Keep this person in mind when you’re trying to figure out what you want to say.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">1. Company History</h2>
<p>The easiest place to start is by telling the story of how your shop came to be. This works well if your store has been open for a long time, even if you only recently started selling online. Start at the very beginning with the original founders and their reasons for starting the business. If your history starts to get too long, break it down into major milestones, then plot them on a timeline. Too many key events? Opt for milestones that interest the audience. For example, the date you joined the company may be interesting to you, but not to your audience.</p>
<p>If you’ve just launched your online business, don’t make up a company history. Nothing destroys trust faster than finding out a merchant lied. Rather than focusing on company history, you can choose to highlight your professional or personal life. Just be sure it adds to the story of your shop; otherwise, simply leave this section out.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">2. Share Your Passion</h2>
<p>Ask yourself, “What do I love about what I do?” and “Why?”</p>
<p>Deep down, you already know why you love what you do, this page is where you can share that with your customers. If you’re not quite sure why you sell the product you’ve selected, you’ll have to dig deep and think.  No matter what you love or why you love it, someone will be able to relate to it – as long as it’s authentic. In other words, if you’re still not sure about your answer, don’t make something up!</p>
<p>Sharing why you love what you do makes the shopping experience more personable for the customer. Customers are no longer making a purchase from just another website. They are making a purchase from someone who shares the same or a similar passion.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">3. Company Mission or Vision</h2>
<p>If your product or service is “revolutionary”, it is crucial that you include your company mission or vision. Use this opportunity to detail the problem that your product/service solves for your customer. Then share your expectations for the future of your company. Sharing your company vision helps sell potential customers on the idea behind a new product. If they weren’t completely sold on the product, this is your last opportunity to convert them.</p>
<p>If you sell regular products that aren’t new, listing your company mission or vision can also help define your shop’s overall goals. Again, make sure that if you include your mission, it must be relatable for the reader.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">4. List Partner Companies</h2>
<p>Work with some great companies? Show them off while you leverage their credibility – just be sure you have permission to use their logos. Here are examples of types of companies you can list:</p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li><strong>Investors</strong> – Any company or individual person who has given your company money</li>
<li><strong>Suppliers</strong> – The company you purchase products from</li>
<li><strong>Manufacturers</strong> – The company or brand that makes the product</li>
<li><strong>Retailers</strong> – A company that sells your products for you in a physical store</li>
<li><strong>“As seen in” publications</strong> – List any notable publications you’ve been featured in</li>
<li><strong>Non-profit organizations</strong> – Include any organizations you donate to or actively support</li>
</ul>
<p>Keep in mind that the focus of this page is to showcase your company. List only the companies that add to your ability to tell your shop’s story.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">5. Testimonials</h2>
<p>If you’re in the habit of brushing off compliments, it’s time to stop. Good customer testimonials can be very helpful in acquiring new customers. When someone offers a compliment, accept it graciously then (if it’s an appropriate time), ask for permission to publish their testimonial.</p>
<p>Don’t have testimonials available? It doesn’t hurt to ask for one. A great time to ask for a testimonial or referral is when you speak directly with a customer who is happy with your product or service. Keep in mind that testimonials don’t always have to come in the form of a traditional quote about your shop.</p>
<p>You can ask customers to like your social media pages to build a presence. External sources of praise for your shop helps you build credibility. Great testimonials reassure potential customers of your product or service.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">6. Images</h2>
<p>Use images to <span style="font-style:italic">show</span> customers what your company is all about. Whether you choose to focus on the staff that runs your website, the working space or company mascot, images can go a long way towards giving customers a firsthand look into your company. Be sure to include a caption for each picture so your audience clearly understands the message you want to get across with your images.</p>
<p>If you choose to use images as the main focus of your “About us” Page, remember that they shouldn’t detract from your company’s narrative. Use them strategically to not only highlight what’s important, but also to connect with the customer.</p>
<h2 style="color:#4d8ab7">Key Takeaways</h2>
<p>About Us pages can help companies connect with their customers. Use one or mix a few of these ideas to get started. Just be sure to keep these tips in mind:</p>
<ul style="padding-left:30px">
<li>Tell your story from the very beginning.</li>
<li>Put your passion front and center.</li>
<li>Share your hopes and dreams through your vision.</li>
<li>Leverage trust from partners.</li>
<li>Build trust with customer testimonials.</li>
<li>Use images to <span style="font-style:italic">illustrate</span> your story.</li>
</ul>
<p>Ready to update your online shop’s About Us page? What are you waiting for? From your PrestaShop back office, navigate to Preferences &gt; CMS &gt; About Us. Want to see some examples? Check out the <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/showcase">PrestaShop showcase</a>. Let us know your favorite examples in the comments below.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/">6 Simple Content Ideas for your About Us Page</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-simple-content-ideas-us-page/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Reasons your online store needs a Custom Domain Name</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2015 16:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve opened an online business with PrestaShop, then you know that we provide your store with a free domain name &#8211; [ShopName].PSwebstore.com. While this domain name will definitely get the job of pointing visitors to your shop done, you might want to consider giving your store its own custom domain name. To help you [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/">5 Reasons your online store needs a Custom Domain Name</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve opened an online business with PrestaShop, then you know that we provide your store with a free domain name &#8211; [ShopName].PSwebstore.com. While this domain name will definitely get the job of pointing visitors to your shop done, you might want to consider giving your store its own custom domain name. To help you decide if this is right for your business, check out our 5 reasons your online store needs a custom domain name.<br />
<span id="more-20004"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Looks Professional</h2>
<p>They say first impressions are lasting impressions. Before a customer lands on your website, they need to enter a web address. While [ShopName].PSwebstore.com may describe what your shop does, it doesn’t look professional. Just put yourself in your customers’ shoes. How much money would you spend on a shop hosted on the PSwebstore domain?</p>
<p>Having a custom domain name helps add credibility to your online store. Your homepage URL changes from [ShopName].PSwebstore.com to something along the lines of www. [ShopName].com. It’s hard to build trust in your shop, so it’s important to take advantage of this opportunity!</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Professional Email</h2>
<p>The second most important reason you need a custom domain name is the professional email address. Along with looking professional, it shows potential business partners that you’ve put time and effort into your shop. Now put yourself in your potential partners&#8217; shoes. Would you prefer to be emailing bob@shopname.com or BobShop@gmail.com?</p>
<p>Not convinced? Would you want to work with a person that emails you from contact@shopname.com or PrestaShopcontact@aol.com? It’s superficial, but having a professional email can go a long way in convincing businesses to work with you and more importantly – take you seriously as a small business owner.</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Search Engine Optimized</h2>
<p>You’ve probably heard lots about <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/find-the-right-seo-keywords-for-your-online-store/">the importance of SEO</a> for your online store. What you probably haven’t heard is that having a custom domain name can help your SEO. How? The first reason is that none of your customers will be searching for “PSwebstore”. The domain you choose will help you rank higher for those keywords than the domain name we’ve provided.</p>
<p>Second, the goal behind SEO is to help customers find your shop. A custom domain name helps you market your shop and brand, making it easier for you to stand out from your competitors and help customers find you. If you choose a relevant domain name with great keywords, it will be listed on every product page.</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Safeguard your brand</h2>
<p>It’s nearly impossible, or at least very expensive, to purchase a domain once it’s been taken by someone else. There’s a whole <a href="https://blog.asmallorange.com/2013/07/how-to-buy-a-domain-name-thats-already-taken/" target="_blank">process for trying to get the domain</a> you want, but it’s never guaranteed. So before you start building up your brand, make sure you’re promoting a brand with a domain name you’ll have access to.</p>
<p>Take, for example, my new favorite sunscreen brand, Sun Bum. When I typed in <a href="http://sunbum.com/" target="_blank">SunBum.com</a>, I was greeted with a parked domain. I automatically assumed that they didn’t have an online shop. What I later discovered was that they did have an online presence, but the URL is <a href="http://trustthebum.com/" target="_blank">http://trustthebum.com/</a>. Instead of the brand name, their URL is their slogan. Although some people (like me) figured it out eventually, consider all the customers who won’t. If you’re building a brand, claim your name. You’ll benefit from both the traffic you get, and you’ll be able to dictate the brand message.</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">Relatively Cheap</h2>
<p>“Okay, these all seem like valid reasons, but how much will it cost me,” you ask. If you already have a PrestaShop store, you can purchase a domain for $16.66 (+ tax) a year. Think of it as trading in 4 coffeehouse drinks throughout the year! If you’re not convinced to spend that money, remember that you may have to pay a premium fee if someone else already owns that domain name. In 2013, the <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/martinzwilling/2013/01/14/get-a-domain-name-without-bankrupting-your-startup/" target="_blank">cost of a domain that was already reserved averaged around $5,000</a>.</p>
<p>If you’re on a tight budget, you can purchase the domain name first (without hosting). Once you start acquiring more funds then, then add the hosting and start building your online presence. (Or you can launch your <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/">PrestaShop Cloud store</a> with free hosting included!)</p>
<h2 style="color: #4e8999">In a Nutshell</h2>
<p>Custom domain names offer an affordable way to look professional, optimize for search engines and, most importantly, protect your brand.</p>
<hr align="left" width="20%" />
<p>Have we convinced you that your online store needs a custom domain name? Start brainstorming ideas then check out this article about <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-pick-the-right-domain-name-for-your-online-store/">picking the right domain for your online shop</a>! Then log into your <a href="http://prestashop.com/">PrestaShop.com</a> account to register and purchase your domain name.</p>
<p>Not an online merchant yet? Get started selling online with PrestaShop’s free, hosted online shopping cart software!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/">5 Reasons your online store needs a Custom Domain Name</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-reasons-online-store-needs-custom-domain-name/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ecommerce 101: How to find the right hosting for your online store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-find-right-hosting-online-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-find-right-hosting-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 14:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=20017</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to setting up an online shop, one of the first things you need to consider are your hosting options. With PrestaShop, you can opt to use our hosted version, PrestaShop cloud, or download the software onto the host of your choice. In this article, we’ll cover the basic elements you should consider [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-find-right-hosting-online-store/">Ecommerce 101: How to find the right hosting for your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to setting up an online shop, one of the first things you need to consider are your hosting options. With PrestaShop, you can opt to use our hosted version, PrestaShop cloud, or download the software onto the host of your choice. In this article, we’ll cover the basic elements you should consider when you’re picking a hosting provider for your ecommerce website.</p>
<p>Today I’ve interviewed PrestaShop developer, Joe Siwiak about the basics of hosting. Read on to decide which hosting will work for your online shop.<br />
<span id="more-20017"></span><br />
There are 3 major types of hosting option: shared hosting, VPS hosting and dedicated hosting.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20021" alt="Shared Hosting" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/Shared-Hosting.jpg" width="796" height="500" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #25b9d7">Shared Hosting</h2>
<p>As the name suggests, you share the hosting with other websites. This may be the most affordable option, but it comes with its drawbacks. The most notable disadvantage to using shared hosting is the limited amount of traffic you can receive on your website at a given time. It’s great when you’re just starting out but if you are expecting a large amount of traffic, this is not the option for you. Once you reach your limit, most shared hosting providers will throttle (or slow down) the load speed of your website.</p>
<p>As the name suggests, you share the hosting with other websites. This may be the most affordable option, but it comes with its drawbacks. The most notable disadvantage to using shared hosting is the limited amount of traffic you can receive on your website at a given time. It’s great when you’re just starting out but if you are expecting a large amount of traffic, this is not the option for you. Once you reach your limit, most shared hosting providers will throttle (or slow down) the load speed of your website.</p>
<p>Another key factor to keep in mind is that if another website on your shared host takes up too much data, your own website performance may be impacted.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20022" alt="VPS Hosting" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/VPS-Hosting.jpg" width="796" height="500" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #25b9d7">VPS Hosting</h2>
<p>The biggest difference between VPS hosting and shared hosting is having dedicated resources for your website. Although you’ll be sharing space on a host with other sites, each will be allotted its own set of resources. This also means you’ll have control over the maintenance and performance of your website. Also, because you have your own set of resources, traffic to other websites will not affect yours.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-20018" alt="Dedicated Hosting" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/Dedicated-Hosting.jpg" width="796" height="500" /></p>
<h2 style="color: #25b9d7">Dedicated Hosting</h2>
<p>This is one of the best hosting options available. Your website is hosted on an individual server, which means you have complete control over both your website and the server. Although this type of hosting is more expensive than VPS hosting, you only pay for the space and performance you need.</p>
<p>Keep in mind that having control over your own server may mean you need a dedicated IT team to maintain your website. But don&#8217;t panic: most dedicated hosting options give you the option to purchase hosting “managed” or “unmanaged”. This service is useful for those that understand the concepts of system administration but not necessarily the syntax/vernacular of the specific operating systems being implemented.</p>
<p>Regardless of the type of hosting you pick, be sure to consider these 5 features of hosting:</p>
<ol>
<li>The <strong>CPU (Central Processing Unit)</strong> is responsible for processing the data on any computer. Because a hosting provider is essentially a large network of computers with even larger storage, your host’s CPU will determine the speed at which information on your website is processed and sent to your browser. Today, customers expect websites to load quickly so it is important that your host has a fast CPU.</li>
<li><strong>RAM (Random Access Memory)</strong> refers to the temporary data stored on a server. RAM is where the “live” part of any system is. It’s used to store information that is either waiting to be processed or information that needs to be accessed immediately. It’s the middle-man that receives instructions from a command (click) and tells the CPU what to process. A slow RAM may cause even a fast CPU to process information slowly. Having a fast RAM is important because whether you’re creating your shop or customers are browsing products, these tasks should be consistently executed on time.</li>
<li><strong>Storage Memory</strong> refers to the amount of information or data you can store on your host. For your online store, data can take the form of the PrestaShop software, order data, customer information and even product images. (The initial installation of PrestaShop software itself takes up 23 MB of memory).</li>
<li><strong>File Access (I/O)</strong> measures the speed at which files can be processed. PrestaShop’s default theme is built on SMARTY template technology, which compiles html templates that are stored as files for later access to reduce the amount of processing your site needs on a user-by-user basis. The template adapts to the configuration of your shop; with our live edit function, you can easily modify key colors and text on your website. Your host’s ability to display your shop’s theme is affected by how fast it can access and assemble the files.</li>
<li><strong>Network Access Speed</strong> refers to the speed at which data is transferred from the server or host to the client&#8217;s computer. Once all the information is processed on the host, sending that information over to the user (whether it’s you or your customer) is key. Without a decent network access speed, your website will load slowly. Not only will you lose potential customers, you will waste time waiting for your own website to load.</li>
</ol>
<p>Now that you know what to look for in a hosting provider, shop for the right one for your new online. Get started with our our preferred list of <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-hosting">hosting partners</a>.</p>
<p>If self-hosting your online shop isn’t right for you, check out the hosted and <em>free</em> version of our software &#8211; <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/ecommerce-software">PrestaShop Cloud</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-find-right-hosting-online-store/">Ecommerce 101: How to find the right hosting for your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/ecommerce-101-find-right-hosting-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Part 1: 7 customer fears and how to address them</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-1-7-customer-fears-address/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-1-7-customer-fears-address/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 08:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19986</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Ecommerce is no longer the intimidating final frontier of retail it once was; customers are used to shopping or at least browsing online. But that doesn’t mean they don’t worry about things like credit card theft or hidden costs. In this two-part article, we’ll address 7 major fears customers have about shopping online, and give [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-1-7-customer-fears-address/">Part 1: 7 customer fears and how to address them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ecommerce is no longer the intimidating final frontier of retail it once was; customers are used to shopping or at least browsing online. But that doesn’t mean they don’t worry about things like credit card theft or hidden costs.</p>
<p>In this two-part article, we’ll address 7 major fears customers have about shopping online, and give you some ideas about how to address them all from first click to final sale.<br />
<span id="more-19986"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #252934">1. It’s not a real store.</h2>
<p>Don’t let your shop be mistaken for a hollow storefront hiding a mail fraud scheme. Reassure your customers that there is a healthy business behind your homepage with the following tips:</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.azaleasf.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Invest in good design</strong></a>. Gaudy colors and a 15-font graphic chart have been out of style since Rupert Murdoch bought MySpace. Good design is worth the investment. Not only does it make navigating your website and finding products (and purchasing them) easier, it shows you care about your business. After all, if you don’t care about your shop, why should your customers?</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19989" alt="Azalea" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/Azalea-1024x660.png" width="700" height="451" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">Azalea’s simple, modern design is easy on the eyes&#8211;and easy to navigate.</span></p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.starcowparis.com/" target="_blank"><strong>List a physical address</strong></a>. You must have an address for receiving professional mail, even if it’s just a post office box, so include it on your “Contact” or “About” page. If you have a physical store or headquarters, you can add a Google Maps locator for added credibility.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19993" alt="Starcow" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/Starcow-1024x531.png" width="700" height="362" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">Starcow’s physical address is discreet, but visible, at the top of their homepage.</span></p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.whatgoesaroundnyc.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Show real photos</strong></a>. Stock photos maybe be cheap and easy to come by, but they do your business no favors. A “Team” or “About” page with a nice photo of yourself or your team members gives you a simple way to connect with your customers and show off your company’s unique personality.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19987" alt="what goes around" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/what-goes-around-1024x637.jpg" width="700" height="435" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">The owners of What Goes Around Comes Around used an authentic photo to complement their brand story.</span></p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.teaguys.com/content/4-about-the-tea-guys" target="_blank"><strong>Tell a story</strong></a>. You’re not like all the other stores out there are you? Let your customers know what makes you different. In addition to a photo or two of you and your VP of Operations (aka your pitbull Greg), give your customers a little back story. Who are you? Why did you start this business? And what makes your store the best place to go for the products you sell? Letting your customers into your world is a great way to build trust.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19997" alt="The tea guys history" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/The-tea-guys-history-1024x558.jpg" width="700" height="381" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">The Tea Guys use a fun drawing a very personable writing style to connect with customers.</span></p>
<p>- <strong>Publish testimonials</strong>. There is nothing more precious than a word-of-mouth recommendation. If other actual human beings have bought your products and told you how happy they were, put it front and center! Don’t edit out all the less-than-stellar reviews&#8211;no one is perfect 100% of the time. Responding to negative feedback publicly shows you’re on top of things in addition to proving you actually exist.</p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.gretelhome.com/content/12-Press" target="_blank"><strong>Showcase media mentions</strong></a>. Similarly to customer testimonials, mention in media of any kind adds to your credibility.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-19990" alt="gretel_home testimonials" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/gretel_home-testimonials.jpg" width="999" height="852" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">Gretel home puts heavy-hitting media showcases front and center.</span></p>
<h2 style="color: #252934">2. My credit card information is going to get stolen.</h2>
<p>Ecommerce has its good guys and bad guys, like any other industry. Credit card and identity theft are real threats that your customers expect you to protect them from&#8211;it’s your responsibility as an online merchant. Here are a few ways to make sure your customers know you’re with the good guys:</p>
<p>- <strong>Display identifiable trustmarks</strong>. Customers might not recognize your logo on their first visit to your site, but they’re probably familiar with the trusty red McAfee shield, the Better Business Bureau’s sturdy torch and Paypal’s reassuring double-P logo. Choose to work with recognized partners and let their trustworthy reputation rub off on your business.</p>
<p>- <strong>Buy an SSL certificate</strong>. SSL is a cryptographic protocol that secures data sent across pages with a cryptographic key. It’s used to protect credit card transactions and sensitive data like login details, or personal information. In PrestaShop, the back office login, front office account pages and orders can be secured with SSL by default. Once you’ve <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/guest-blogger-series-prestashop-ssl-installation-troubleshooting/">bought and installed your SSL certificate</a>, your customers will recognize your concern for their safety by the reassuring green <em>https</em>&#8211;not the unprotected <span style="font-style: italic">http</span>&#8211;before your website name.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19992" alt="mireness secure" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/mireness-secure-1024x295.jpg" width="700" height="201" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">The green lock and https before Mirenesse’s address indicate that the site is secure.</span></p>
<p>- <a href="http://www.headict.co.uk/content/5-secure-payment" target="_blank"><strong>Give customers payment options</strong></a>. Some people just aren’t into paying by credit card. By giving the option to pay using Paypal, by check or simply on delivery, you show that you’re flexible and willing to adapt to your customers’ needs.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19991" alt="headict secure payment" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/headict-secure-payment-1024x373.jpg" width="700" height="254" /></p>
<p><span style="font-style: italic">In addition to directly addressing payment security, Headict displays trusted payment partners on a dedicated page.</span></p>
<h2 style="color: #252934">3. They’ll sell my personal information.</h2>
<p>In this era of big data, everyone wants to know what’s going to happen once they give up their email, phone number, date of birth and favorite color. Having and displaying a complete privacy policy should be one of the first things you add to your site. Make sure it answers the questions:</p>
<p>What information is collected?<br />
How is the information used?<br />
How is the information shared?<br />
What choices do customers have for sharing information?<br />
How can customers access and modify their personal information?<br />
How is the information protected?</p>
<p>Here’s an example to follow:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-19994" alt="target" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/05/target-1024x768.jpg" width="700" height="525" /></p>
<p>Target’s <a href="http://www.target.com/spot/privacy-policy#?lnk=fnav_t_spc_2_3&amp;intc=28073%7Cnull" target="_blank">privacy policy</a> leaves no question unanswered.</p>
<p>What other customer fears have you encountered? Let us know in the comments. And stayed tuned for part 2! Ready to start an online business customers can trust? <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/">Create your online store with PrestaShop today</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-1-7-customer-fears-address/">Part 1: 7 customer fears and how to address them</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/part-1-7-customer-fears-address/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>30 Call to Action Verbs for your online store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/30-call-action-verbs-online-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/30-call-action-verbs-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 16:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19982</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Call to action (CTA) buttons are essential for converting visitors that land on your website. Great CTA buttons engage the shopper and entice them to complete an action, from adding products to a cart to making purchases. Just as your website design and products give your website character, the words you choose for your CTA [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/30-call-action-verbs-online-store/">30 Call to Action Verbs for your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-importance-of-call-to-action-buttons-on-your-e-commerce-site/">Call to action (CTA) buttons are essential</a> for converting visitors that land on your website. Great CTA buttons engage the shopper and entice them to complete an action, from adding products to a cart to making purchases.</p>
<p>Just as your website design and products give your website character, the words you choose for your CTA buttons can give your site an edge. Making subtle changes to your Call to Action text can impact your shop’s effectiveness.Today we’re sharing 30 call to action verbs to liven up your online store.<br />
<span id="more-19982"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #5aab20">CTAs for adding an item to the shopping cart</h2>
<p>The most common call to action button is one that prompts customers to add items to their carts. The default text on PrestaShop stores, is “Add to Cart”. While this makes it crystal clear what you want your customers to do, there are a few other ways to deliver the same message:</p>
<ol>
<li>Shop</li>
<li>Buy</li>
<li>Get</li>
<li>Purchase</li>
<li>Order</li>
<li>I <strong>want</strong> this!</li>
<li>Add to… Tote / Basket / Luggage / Box (or anything related to your business)</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="color: #5aab20">CTAs for purchasing digital products</h2>
<p>A growing segment in ecommerce is the <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-benefits-selling-digital-products-online/">sale of digital products</a>. You can use the same CTAs as your would for traditional merchandise, or you can customize them for digital products. Depending on what you’re selling, try the following:</p>
<ol start="8">
<li>Download</li>
<li>Watch</li>
<li>Read</li>
<li>Reserve</li>
<li>Schedule</li>
<li>Book</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="color: #5aab20">CTAs for requesting additional details</h2>
<p>Whether customers are browsing your home, category or product page, you should always lead them towards a conversion. For customers who aren’t quite ready to make the purchase, sway their decision by providing more information about the product. Consider using:</p>
<ol start="14">
<li>Request</li>
<li>Find</li>
<li>Uncover</li>
<li>Learn</li>
<li>Discover</li>
<li>Explore</li>
<li>Browse</li>
<li>Compare</li>
<li>See more</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="color: #5aab20">CTAs for engagement</h2>
<p>Sometimes you just want customers to join your community. Whether they subscribe to your newsletters or become your fan on social media, each action helps you reach potential customers. For these CTA’s, your goal is to get customers to want to interact with you. It’s why you want these CTA’s to be very clear and specific. Include one or many of the verbs listed below:</p>
<ol start="23">
<li>Call</li>
<li>Ask</li>
<li>Live Chat</li>
<li>Subscribe</li>
<li>Contact us</li>
<li>Register</li>
<li>Sign Up</li>
<li>Like, Tweet, Follow (any other social media verbs)</li>
</ol>
<p>No matter what action you’re trying to entice customers to complete, remember that each button should resonate with the reader. By aligning the verb you choose with the action and your customers place in your conversion funnel, you increase your chances for converting them.</p>
<p>Are you ready to refine your online shop with our list of call to action verbs? Edit your call to action text directly from your back office.</p>
<ol>
<li>Click Localization &gt; Translations.</li>
<li>Under the “Modify Translations” tab, select “Front-office translations”, your theme, and the language you’d like to work on, and then click “Modify”.</li>
</ol>
<p>Want more ideas for improving your call to action buttons? Check out our list of <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/15-examples-of-cta-buttons-to-drive-conversions-for-online-stores/">15 examples of CTA’s that drive conversions for online stores</a>.<br />
Not an online merchant yet? Get started today with PrestaShop Cloud for a fully-hosted online shop – for free! What are you waiting for?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/30-call-action-verbs-online-store/">30 Call to Action Verbs for your online store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/30-call-action-verbs-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A beginner’s guide to designing lead magnets</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-designing-lead-magnets/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-designing-lead-magnets/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 14:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19924</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>It takes time to build trust, instill confidence and build a relationship with your customers. Let’s face it: most of them won’t buy anything on their first visit. Customers are either browsing, doing market research and comparative analysis or not entirely sure your offer is what they need. It’s why you’ll need something to engage [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-designing-lead-magnets/">A beginner’s guide to designing lead magnets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It takes time to build trust, instill confidence and build a relationship with your customers. Let’s face it: most of them won’t buy anything on their first visit. Customers are either browsing, doing market research and comparative analysis or not entirely sure your offer is what they need. It’s why you’ll need something to engage your customers with something we call a “lead magnet.”</p>
<p>Today <a href="https://psaddons.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">technical blogger</a> specializing in PrestaShop and ecommerce consultant, <a href="https://twitter.com/AmeliaJohns89" target="_blank">Amelia Johns</a> shares her beginner’s guide to designing lead magnets. Read on to learn more. <span id="more-19924"></span></p>
<h4><span style="color: #eb4245"><strong>What is a lead magnet?</strong></span></h4>
<p>A lead magnet is the (free) offer you make on your website in exchange for visitors’ email addresses. Since we all hesitate to provide information on the internet, you must gain your customers trust by offering them something in return.</p>
<p>The goal of a lead magnet is to maximize the number of targeted leads you receive in exchange for an offer and can be considered the first step in your customer value optimization process.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #eb4245"><strong>Why Use Lead Magnets?</strong></span></h4>
<p>Lead magnets are sales catalysts. Driving traffic to your website is not enough to have a positive impact on your business. In order for those visitors to provide any value to your company, they need to become subscribers, leads or customers through your website. Lead magnets capitalize on specific incentives offered on your lead generation or ‘landing’ page to convert visitors into customers.</p>
<p>“Potential” becomes “profitable” as your customer base expands rapidly and extensively. When you offer your users something that makes them super-excited, you get the job done easily&#8211;the trick is to combine usefulness with interest.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #eb4245"><strong>Examples of great Lead Magnets:</strong></span></h4>
<p><img class="alignleft size-large wp-image-19963" alt="lead-magnets-1" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/lead-magnets-1-1024x516.png" width="700" height="352" /><br />
Moz offers a free 30-day trial to get more daily signups.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-19964" alt="lead-magnets-2" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/lead-magnets-2.png" width="895" height="355" /><br />
Robbie Richards uses a beautiful call to action, ‘Let’s Do This!’, to encourage visitors to sign up for his newsletter offering advice on how to increase website traffic.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-large wp-image-19965" alt="lead-magnets-3" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/lead-magnets-3-1024x511.png" width="700" height="349" /><br />
Another great example from Robbie, offering ebook downloads as a lead magnet.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #eb4245"><strong>The Math behind Lead Magnets</strong></span></h4>
<p>A strong Lead Magnet will boost your revenue generation stream by minimizing missed opportunities. The following table provides a quick overview of the figures that prove the necessity of having a good magnet in place.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-19966" alt="lead-magnets-4-chart" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/lead-magnets-4-chart.png" width="618" height="258" /></p>
<h4><span style="color: #eb4245"><strong>Different Kinds of Lead Magnets</strong></span></h4>
<p>The kind of lead magnets you offer will vary depending on if you’re providing a service or selling physical products. While the form may differ, in both cases the more valuable your lead magnet is to your ideal customer, the more likely they will be to use it. There are many different lead magnets to choose from, so avoid copy-pasting. Identify what you want to achieve and choose your lead magnet accordingly. Here are some examples of popular lead magnets:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Offer free software downloads or a trial version.</strong>Anyone who wants to see the product in action enters their email address. Then they are immediately taken through an interactive demo of how the tool works.</li>
<li><strong>Checklists and handouts. </strong>They are generally very short (one page or so) and cut straight to an ultra-specific point and they can be delivered as checklists, mind maps or templates. They help customers work through a complicated project without missing any key pieces.</li>
<li><strong>Quiz or Survey. </strong>This can be a very engaging way to generate new leads by sending the quiz results via email. Quiz building tools like Interact make it easy to generate fun, entertaining quizzes.</li>
<li><strong>Video trainings or webinars. </strong>These can be excellent tools if you feel they’re aligned with your business offering and you have development resources. Video can be a very effective way to deliver a lead magnet; simple screen cast tools like Camtasia or Screenflow make delivery easy.</li>
<li><strong>Free Shipping and Bonus Offers. </strong>Provide customers with one or more offers to join your email newsletter (or any other subscription list) with the promise of coupons and special deals like seasonal discounts or members’ only sales.</li>
<li><strong>Toolkits </strong>are one of those lead magnet examples that has worked to get massive results with seemingly little effort. It is a super simple landing page offering visitors a free PDF report with a super simple list of tools. That is it! Visitors arrive on the page and read the sales copy with the offer. Then they decide to enter their email to get the report delivered to their inbox, or not.</li>
<li><strong>Free Consultation or Buying Guides or Sales materials. </strong>The most desired piece of information for the market is pricing and descriptions of products or services. Often in their look out for the best deal out there, users will be willing to provide their email address for securing such treasured information for existing deals, and for the future.</li>
<li><strong>Free eBooks or Reports</strong>are another popular type of lead magnets. You offer value in news, best practices, or advice, and visitors must fill out the form to opt-in and receive the free PDF via email.</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<h4><span style="color: #eb4245"><strong>Building an Attractive Lead Magnet</strong></span></h4>
<p>Lead Magnets do not have to be lengthy. Or complex. Or time-intensive to create. The key is to build a tool that solves a specific problem with a specific solution for a specific segment of your market. In order for your lead magnet to be effective, it has to be consumed by the consumer. The perfect Lead Magnet will offer tremendous value within 5 minutes of the opt-in. Just ask yourself the following questions:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>What offers will I make to new leads?</li>
<li>How well do these offers convert?</li>
<li>How much is a visit to my lead magnet landing page worth?</li>
<li>How much is a new lead worth?</li>
<li>How much is a new sale worth?</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>With the right Lead Magnet in place and systematically defined support processes behind it, your business will become a lead and sales generating machine.</p>
<h4><span style="color: #eb4245"><strong>Takeaways </strong></span></h4>
<p>Here are a few points to keep in mind when you get ready to develop lead magnets:</p>
<ol>
<ul>
<li>Understand what your ‘ideal’ prospect really wants</li>
<li>A good lead magnet creates ‘aha’ moments</li>
<li>Don’t go with the flow. Be contrarian. Dare to be disruptive.</li>
<li>Specificity: Offer something that clearly leads to your product or solution</li>
<li>Offer something that helps makes prospects a buying decision</li>
<li>The perceived value of the magnet should surpass the reluctance of a mildly interested browser in giving up their personal information</li>
<li>Emphasize on the ‘shareability’ of the magnet</li>
<li>Be simplistic. Do not let superfluous ingenuity compromise the value creation of the magnet</li>
</ul>
</ol>
<p>___________</p>
<p>Which lead magnet are you looking forward to trying out? Tell us in the comments below. Not selling online yet? Launch your online store with <a href="http://www.prestashop.com" target="_blank">PrestaShop Cloud </a>– our still free and hosted version!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-designing-lead-magnets/">A beginner’s guide to designing lead magnets</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/beginners-guide-designing-lead-magnets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 tips for a successful sales campaign</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-tips-successful-sales-campaign/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-tips-successful-sales-campaign/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 12:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19881</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>While no business can or should depend on sales promotions alone for communicating and connecting with customers, they are an important part of building customer relationships. When used as part of an integrated marketing strategy, sales promotions can help to increase traffic, reinforce visibility and drive sales. The five tips presented in today’s post should [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-tips-successful-sales-campaign/">5 tips for a successful sales campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While no business can or should depend on sales promotions alone for communicating and connecting with customers, they are an important part of building customer relationships. When used as part of an <a href="http://smallbusiness.chron.com/importance-integrated-marketing-communications-73248.html" target="_blank">integrated marketing strategy</a>, sales promotions can help to increase traffic, reinforce visibility and drive sales.</p>
<p>The five tips presented in today’s post should give you food for thought for building your next sales campaign.<br />
<span id="more-19881"></span></p>
<h2 style="color: #fd5a0f">1/ Understand your audience</h2>
<p>Before you start scheduling an email campaign or drafting popups for your homepage, take some to think about who you’re targeting and what you want to achieve. You’ve probably got a diverse customer base, so if you haven’t already, identify different segments and <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">create appropriate customer personas</a>.</p>
<p>Ask yourself: what are my customers’ needs? What do they expect from my product?</p>
<p>The answers are likely to be different for each segment. Keep them in mind as you create tailored content that resonates with your target audience.</p>
<p>Also, think about what results you want to achieve.</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Are you purely after an increase in sales and traffic?</li>
<li>Are you just trying to clear slow-moving inventory?</li>
<li>Or are you also interested in strengthening your lead base? (If so, you’ll need to integrate a method of collecting emails and other customer information into your campaign.)</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #fd5a0f">2/ Choose your moment</h2>
<p>Sales campaigns often revolve around a major holiday or event, such as the back-to-school season or Christmas. You can also set up flash sales or special offers to reward customers on a more personalized basis. If you’re not sure where to start, you’ll want to check out what your competitors are doing. Then ask:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Will you be overlapping a similar campaign?</li>
<li>Can you differentiate yourself with a more compelling offer?</li>
<li>What does their campaign look like visually and can you be more engaging?</li>
<li>Now is also the time to think about budget and resources.</li>
<li>Can you create all your marketing materials yourself?</li>
<li>Do you need to call on the skills of a graphic designer or photographer?</li>
<li>Do you have time to manage the emailing portion of your campaign?</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color: #fd5a0f">3/ Make a plan</h2>
<p>Once you’ve decided who you want to target and when you want to launch your campaign, you can <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/375-e-commerce-calendar" target="_blank">start mapping out your calendar</a>. If you’re running a holiday-specific campaign, you’ll want to get content together ahead of time. This way you can start teasing customers with deals and product guides several weeks in advance—in other words, don’t wait until February 1st to start thinking about Valentine’s Day promotions. Ask yourself these questions as you put together your plan:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>What incentive will you offer your customers?</li>
<li>How often will you communicate with them over the length of the promotion?</li>
</ul>
<p>Use your customer personas to create personalized messages that you can promote across communication channels.</p>
<h2 style="color: #fd5a0f">4/ Harmonize across channels</h2>
<p>To maximize the impact of your promotion, consider how you’ll push it through your various communication channels, adapting the message to each outlet, i.e. website, email, social media, traditional media. You may want to roll out your campaign in different phases, teasing on social media and sending targeted emails with highly-perishable discount offers that communicate a sense of urgency and compel customers to respond to your call to action. Consistency is key to communicating reliability and credibility, which will also have an impact on how customers see your brand in the long run.</p>
<h2 style="color: #fd5a0f">5/ Track, test, improve</h2>
<p>Use analytics tools to gather data about how your campaign performed with different customer segments. You can use A/B testing to try out variations on elements like emails, landing page and calls to action. Be prepared to spend some time on this and don’t worry if it takes a while to get the performance you expect. The only way you can find out what’s working is to gather the data and compare the impact of changes you make. Also be sure to set a timeframe for your promotion. This will allow you to evaluate the impact of duration and seasonality when you look at your tracked data.</p>
<p>Got a tip for successful sales campaigns you don’t see here? Share with the community in the comments. Ready to start your own successful ecommerce store? Get PrestaShop today.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-tips-successful-sales-campaign/">5 tips for a successful sales campaign</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-tips-successful-sales-campaign/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Online store web design: homepage structure</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-web-design-homepage-structure/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-web-design-homepage-structure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 10:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juan Manuel Molina]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19925</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Redesigning your online store is easier than you think. But before you select colors, fonts and images, you need a clear idea of what your homepage structure will look like. Ask yourself the following questions: What information is essential for my customers? Where and how can I position this information? In this post, we outline [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-web-design-homepage-structure/">Online store web design: homepage structure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Redesigning your online store is easier than you think. But before you select colors, fonts and images, you need a clear idea of what your homepage structure will look like. Ask yourself the following questions:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>What information is essential <strong>for my customers</strong>?</li>
<li>Where and how can I position this information?</li>
</ul>
<p>In this post, we outline the essential elements of any online store&#8217;s homepage. Adapt them to your needs to design a homepage that increases sales and strengthens your brand image.<br />
<span id="more-19925"></span></p>
<p>Before we begin, keep in mind that: in most cases, the order of the information on the page depends on its importance and how it will be used. To understand what information your customers need, <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/how-to-develop-buyer-personas-for-b2c-ecommerce-marketing/">define your ideal customer</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="search" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Search.png" width="50" height="50" /> Search bar</h2>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/travel/19445-traveler-prestashop-16-responsive-theme.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-12827" alt="searchbar1" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/searchbar1-1024x537.jpg" width="700" height="367" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/food-drinks/19451-sushi-house-16-responsive.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-12828" alt="searchbar2" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/searchbar2-1024x537.jpg" width="700" height="367" /></a></p>
<p>Make products easier to find with a highly visible search bar located in the center or top left-hand corner of your page. Many of your customers already know what they want so you just have to help them find it.</p>
<p>On the mobile version of your website, try to position the search bar as close to the top of the page as possible: just after the logo and, ideally, next to the menu icon.</p>
<p>Bonus: From the results page, let customers add the product directly into the shopping cart.</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="shopping" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Shopping.png" width="50" height="50" /> Shopping cart or basket</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.mackweldon.com/cart" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-12830" alt="shopping-cart" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/shopping-cart-1024x537.jpg" width="700" height="367" /></a></p>
<p>Adding products to a cart can be fun and even addictive! Use emotional design techniques to transform the shopping experience into something enjoyable and memorable.</p>
<p>If your brand allows, adapt the tone of voice and word choice of your shopping cart buttons and calls to action to match the category of your products, seasons, campaigns, etc.</p>
<p><strong>Try using humor</strong> in your status bars and notifications &#8212; but remember to avoid offending your target customer. If you apply humor to your text, <strong>don’t forget to keep the design of your buttons and links consistent</strong> so you don’t confuse customers.</p>
<p>Bonus: Leverage gamification to encourage users to add more products to the cart. For example, indicate the amount remaining to obtain a free delivery in a progress bar or attract customer to unlock &#8216;levels&#8217; based on the products (e.g., fan, handyman, expert).</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="slider" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Slider.png" width="50" height="50" /> Slider</h2>
<p>Ideally a slider should include one fixed slide, and never more than three rotating slides. Use these slider to display seasonal promotions, new items and product selections or, even better, selections of discounted products adapted to a seasonal campaign (Father&#8217;s Day, Mother&#8217;s Day, Christmas, back to school, etc.).</p>
<p>Customer should always be able to know what you sell directly from the slider. <strong>Display your products in a setting</strong> with an attractive background image that fills the space and an interesting text and call to action, adapted to the spirit of the promotion.</p>
<p>Bonus: Discover some of the best examples of full-screen slider images in our article, <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-ecommerce-design-trends-2015/">5 E-commerce design trends for 2015</a>.</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="menu" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Menu.png" width="50" height="50" /> Menu</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.bershka.com/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-12822" alt="menu" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/menu-1024x537.jpg" width="700" height="367" /></a></p>
<p>Most merchants think that the menu is the first thing that customers should see when they visit your website… but it doesn’t have to be.</p>
<p>If the customers are browsing your site from a mobile device, it may be better to offer a search option and put the menu in an attractive drop-down. On larger screens, it is easier to browse and there is enough space to show all menu elements. But don’t get carried away and stuff the menu: <strong>it should contain at least 3 but no more than 7 elements</strong>.</p>
<p>Focus on showing your product&#8217;s main categories:</p>
<p>e.g., MEN, WOMEN, CHILDREN.</p>
<p>If you notice a specific product drawing a lot of traffic to your store, don’t hesitate to add it to your menu. SHOES, SCARVES and BAGS are examples of subcategories that you could use in your main menu. GIFTS, VACATION or NEW YEAR&#8217;S EVE can also appear in your menu depending on the time of year. The name of your campaign or current collection could also be used.</p>
<p>Try to keep the menu items as short as possible: two words are fine, but one is better.</p>
<p>If you have a blog, we suggest inserting it in the menu.</p>
<p>In PrestaShop 1.6, you can configure rich drop-down submenus to display products included in the category as well as promotional banners.</p>
<p>Bonus: &#8216;About us&#8217;, &#8216;company&#8217;, &#8216;history&#8217; and similar pages should be kept out of the menu. We suggest placing them in the footer instead, because it’s where visitors expect to find them.</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="filters" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Filters.png" width="50" height="50" /> Filter options</h2>
<p>Filters are normally used on the category and product pages, but they can also be used on the homepage.</p>
<p>Let customers filter by size, color, season, occasion, use, or even cooking technique, among other things. Add all the filters that are helpful for customers shopping for your product. Sometimes it is better to refer to product uses than the object itself. For example:</p>
<p>Frying pans -&gt; for Frying<br />
Pots -&gt; for Boiling</p>
<p>Listen to your users to get the best filters for your product.</p>
<p>With regards placement, it’s generally better to have drop-down filters. If the screen is large, you can display them permanently on the right side of the screen, in browse mode.</p>
<p>Bonus: By default, place a filter on the homepage when the width of the shopper’s screen is greater than 1280 pixels.</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="products" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Product.png" width="50" height="50" /> Products on the homepage</h2>
<p><a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/fashion/19484-watches-store.html" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-12825" alt="Products" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/products-1024x537.jpg" width="700" height="367" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Display the most interesting products on your homepage</strong> whenever there is a reason to do so. It is a good idea to <strong>have two points of entry</strong> (from the menu and homepage) to your product pages.</p>
<p>It is important to tell customers &#8211; with a small title or label &#8211; why the product is on the homepage. Good examples of labels include: new items, best-selling items, discounts, last units in stock, etc. Always highlight the exclusive nature of the group of products or the limited amount of time that the products will be available.</p>
<p>Bonus: Display a maximum of 10 products and activate the &#8216;Product quick view&#8217; option to help customers browse products with few clicks. Users will add these products to their carts without realizing!</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Categories" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Categories.png" width="50" height="50" /> Categories</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.reebok.com/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-12816" alt="categories" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/categories-1024x537.jpg" width="700" height="367" /></a></p>
<p>Continuing with the <strong>two points of entry</strong> or double entry strategy, include a block that shows off your categories with images or icons.</p>
<p>Bonus: Select your most important categories or subcategories and, whenever possible, update them with promotions or product selections.</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Social Media" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Socialmedia.png" width="50" height="50" /> Social Media</h2>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://www.leslipfrancais.fr/en/" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-19949" alt="socialmedia" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/socialmedia-1024x537.jpg" width="700" height="367" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Before the footer</strong>, include a section or several sections where customers can verify that you can be trusted; there is no better way than reading and seeing what customers say about you.</p>
<p><strong>Include images from social media</strong>, stories or any other content created by your customers.</p>
<p>For example, a section can show photos with the hashtag of your last campaign combined with photos from the official brand book or photos of the recipes that you recommend in your blog and cooked by your users with your appliances.</p>
<p>Make use of everything that you can think of to show that you have an audience and that others love you, and so they should too.</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b"><img style="margin-right: 2px" alt="Social Media" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/Footer.png" width="50" height="50" /> Footer</h2>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-12819" alt="footer" src="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2015/04/footer-1024x537.jpg" width="700" height="367" /></p>
<p>Here, insert your <strong>contact options</strong> and links to your social media. This section must visibly contain your website’s <strong>terms and conditions</strong>, particularly those related to <strong>shipping and returns</strong>.</p>
<p>You can also include a newsletter field so users can receive news by Email and, if possible, specify how often the Newsletter is sent.</p>
<p>Finally, use this space to discretely mention your security and trusted systems. If possible, include badges in black and white so you don’t distract customers from your page.</p>
<h2 style="color: #2b2b2b">Conclusion</h2>
<p>Customers form an initial impression of your brand and entire website just by looking at the design and organization of your homepage. Make sure that your website looks smart and professional because it is a great opportunity to gain visibility and trust and decrease your bounce rate.</p>
<p>If you decide to redesign your online store yourself, follow this guide. In the next article, you will be able to learn more about designing an online store as we will look at the structure of the category pages and product pages.</p>
<p>For more options for dressing, check out some of the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/3-templates-prestashop" target="_blank">templates</a> available for PrestaShop. If you want a custom developed design, any of our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">associated web design agencies</a> will be happy to help.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-web-design-homepage-structure/">Online store web design: homepage structure</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-web-design-homepage-structure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get your free ecommerce store evaluation</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Robinson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=19646</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Running an ecommerce business is a lot of work, we get it. It’s easy to lose perspective when you’re juggling so many priorities: is your site design drawing customers or chasing them away? Are you giving customers a memorable shopping experience that will keep them coming back or losing them before they hit checkout? The [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/">Get your free ecommerce store evaluation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Running an ecommerce business is a lot of work, we get it.</p>
<p>It’s easy to lose perspective when you’re juggling so many priorities: is your site design drawing customers or chasing them away? Are you giving customers a memorable shopping experience that will keep them coming back or losing them before they hit checkout?</p>
<p>The beginning of the year is a great time to step back and take a look at your site, before summer sales and the back-to-school season descend upon us (they’ll be here before you know it!). To help give you perspective, we’ve launched an Ecommerce Evaluation of the Month project.<span id="more-19646"></span></p>
<p>Each month, one lucky business owner will get a thorough site evaluation by our in-house ecommerce experts, who will identify what’s working well and what could be tweaked to attract more customers and build a healthy long-term online business. The store will be featured on our blog.</p>
<p>Here are just a few of the things our evaluation will address:</p>
<ul style="margin-left: 30px;font-style: italic">
<li>Traffic</li>
<li>Conversions</li>
<li>User experience</li>
<li>Images</li>
<li>Customer loyalty</li>
</ul>
<p>We’ll publish the evaluations on our blog so everyone in our community can learn from one another and benefit from seeing best practices in action.</p>
<p>Ready to get personalized advice for your ecommerce store and learn from other stores?<br />
Email us at <a href="mailto:ecommerce-evaluation@prestashop.com">ecommerce-evaluation@prestashop.com</a> to enter for a chance to get your free online store evaluation.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/">Get your free ecommerce store evaluation</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-free-ecommerce-store-evaluation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
